# 褪下来了
It’s peeled off.
# 好
Good.
# 再冲一下
Wash it one more time.
# 更脆
Crispier.
# 好嘞
Excellent.
# 鱼香脆皮虾
Fish-flavored crispy prawns.
# 今天咱做一个与众不同的酥皮虾
Today we are bringing a unique recipe of crispy prawns.
# 一个是它的改刀方式
One thing different is its carving.
# 再一个它的口味
Another is its taste.
# 这个一个是小焦来了
Here is my fellow Jiao.
# 一个是你向来都是与众不同是吧
You have always been different, right?
# 关键我来师兄必须做大菜
The key point is that my big bro has to cook serious dishes when I come here.
# 小菜我看不上他呀
Small dishes I can do better.
# 诶 什么虾
What types of prawn it is?
# 海白虾
Sea white shrimp.
# 虾头剪掉 虾腿剪掉
Cut off the head and legs.
# 这个是关键
This is the crucial part.
# 我腹部开刀
Cut along the belly.
# 他这样那皮就整个褪下来了
In this way the shell could be peeled off thoroughly.
# 就跟虾蜕皮似的
It’s like ecdysis mechanism of shrimps themselves.
# 腹开啊 两边腹开
Expose the belly, cut the edges.
# 这菜很快啊
It’s a quick dish.
# 褪下来了好
Peeled off, good.
# 你看三叔揣着兜 检验
Look at Wu, hands in his pocket, checking out right now, haha.
# 这叫检阅
It’s called inspection.
# 虾线必须挑掉
Sand vein must be removed.
# 摘掉
Done.
# 咱们是用几头虾
How many prawns are we gonna use?
# 八个头
Eight.
# 八个头350克大概多少钱
Eight prawns, about 350g, how much it would be around?
# 成本
Cost?
# 40来块钱
40 RMB, a bit more.
# 40多块钱在家做一大菜
You can cook a serious dish at home with this 40 RMB.
# 值 很值
Worthy! Very worthy!
# 咱把这个虾给他冲白了
Wash the prawn until it turns white.
# 把血沫子都给它冲走
Wash out all of the scums.
# 通过凉水这一激 它成型了
Use the cold water to contract the meat. It gone firm now.
# 咱把虾给它沾一下
Let’s get rid of excess water by towel.
# 再给它腌一下
And marinate the prawns.
# 稍微搁点盐
A little bit salt.
# 好料酒（黄酒）来点
A little bit rice wine.
# 少搁点葱姜
Less scallion and ginger.
# 腌多长时间啊
How long it takes?
# 腌 大概个10来分钟
Marinate for a bit more than 10 minutes.
# 好
Ok.
# 咱就给他蘸一下粉子
Sprinkle the starch over the prawns.
# 这是玉米淀粉
This is corn starch.
# 蘸这虾的时候
When sprinkle the starch,
# 千万不能蘸着虾皮
You must not touch the shell.
# 诶 OK
Well, ok.
# 这要待会炸吧
Is it supposed to be fried later?
# 炸完以后它不打卷吗
Aren’t they gonna roll up after fried?
# 要它打卷 就让他打卷
We need them to roll up, so let em be.
# 对 卷起来
Yes, roll up.
# 烧油的同时
When we heat up the oil,
# 来 先把这鱼香汁给调出来
Let’s make this fish-flavored ingredient at the same time.
# 绵白糖 三勺
Three teacup of powdered sugar.
# 醋和糖的比例1：1
The ratio of vinegar to sugar is 1:1
# 黄酒
Rice wine
# 少来点酱油
A pinch of Soy sauce, slightly less than usual.
# 少来 好 调色
A little bit, good, for coloring.
# 少来点胡椒粉
A little bit of pepper.
# 加点水
Add some water.
# 好嘞
Great.
# 这个鱼香口刚才还说了半天
We have been talking about this “fish-flavored taste” for a while.
# 到底是什么口
So what it is exactly?
# 鱼香口应该是酸甜咸鲜
A fish-flavored taste should include vinegar, sweetness, saltiness, and umami.
# 微辣
A little spicy?
# 但是在四川什么味儿
How does it taste in Sichuan cuisine?
# 咸在前 咸甜酸辣香
Saltiness ranks the first, which followed by sweetness, vinegar, spiciness and aroma.
# 有麻味吗
Any numbness?
# 没有
No.
# 刨坑
A trap question.
# 这个是坚决没有
Hahhah definitely not!
# 老同志脑瓜反应快
Old fellow got a quick reflex!
# 所以说三叔你看任何菜都涉及到改良
So, Wu, here it is, any recipes could all be improved and evolved.
# 有好多网友朋友们一说
Many friends would call a recipe “authentic”
# 正宗正宗
authentic, authentic.
# 什么叫正宗
What is “authentic”?
# 三说我是这么觉得
Bro I think it this way.
# 你只要吃好吃 吃满意
As long as it satisfies your taste,
# 这就叫正宗
It could be called “Authentic”.
# 适合你的口味就叫正宗
“Authentic taste” is the taste that suits you.
# 没错
Exactly.
# 真正把川菜拿过来
If I brought you a local Sichuan food here,
# 你其实不一定能吃
You might not get used to it.
# 我老饭骨其实也是秉承这种家庭口味
Our Lao Fan Gu insist on the family taste meals.
# 然后让你吃着很满意的口味
And create tastes that satisfied your taste.
# 让你自己能操作的口味来做咱们
Our cooking instruction mainly focus on some delicious tastes,
# 在自己家里边能做的美食
that you are able cook in your own home.
# 对吧
Right?
# 所以说别拿正宗说事
So forget about “authentic”.
# 来先把虾头炸一下
Let’s fry prawns’ heads first.
# 注意啊 别烫着
Be cautious, don’t burn yourself.
# 得睡醒了
Don’t you fall asleep here.
# 你魏兄是
Your brother, Wei,
# OK
Ok
# 给自己定为梦中人
Always falls in dreams at the middle of the day.
# 漂亮啊 漂亮吧
It looks wonderful, isn’t it?
# 这就OK了
And now it’s done.
# 对
Yes.
# 要的脆劲儿
Crispy is what we need.
# 拿大漏勺
Take a large slotted spoon.
# 油温正好啊 招呼
The oil temperature is perfect. Let’s do it.
# 一个一个的下
We cook them one by one.
# 三个一块下
Three in a time.
# 这虾出来绝对脆
These prawns are definitely gonna be crispy!
# 你听这声儿
You can hear this sound.
# 啪啪
piapiapia
# 这油温有200度 九成油温
The temperature of oil is around 200 Celsius degree, nine tenths of the maximum temp.
# 没有九成油温
Less than nine.
# 这个也就是七成 七到八成
It’s only around seven or eight.
# 九成油温快冒烟了
Oil will be nearly vaporized if it’s at nine tenths.
# 看看
Look at it.
# 还是小焦
Still count on my little brother Jiao.
# 所以三叔说三七二百一么
So as Wu said, seven tenths is 210 Celsius degrees.
# 这个脆皮虾关键皮得脆
The key point of this “ Crispy prawns” is its’ crispness.
# 再复炸一下
Let’s fry one more time.
# 网友朋友们 看看啊
Hey my friends, look at it.
# 这个油温高 看看虾皮是透的
The shell looks transparent as the oil temperature is high.
# 如果油温低 坏了
If the oil temperature is low, it will go bad,
# 乌哒哒
Looks cloudy.
# 再冲一下 更脆
Let’s fry one more time, make it crispier!
# 好嘞
Great!
# 齐活
Perfect!
# 关键你看没有网友们 必须得洗干净了
Hey my friends, noticed that? The key point is to wash until it absolutely clean.
# 看见没有 多亮
Look, how bright it is!
# 里外晶莹剔透
Transparent and crystal both inside and outside.
# 跟穿着一裙子似的
Look like a wonderful dress on the prawn.
# 没错
Exactly.
# 油倒走
Get rid of the oil redundancy.
# 师兄您今儿选择这是什么虾啊
Bro what prawns you choose today?
# 泰国的 海白虾
Thailand, Sea white shrimp.
# 而且得用皮儿薄的
And we select those with thin shells.
# 其实我觉着一通百通
In fact, I think if you know one method you will know all.
# 有什么拿什么
You can cook whatever in your hands.
# 做出来按这种手法都好看
Followed this recipe, they all gonna be excellent.
# 对
Yes.
# 现在开始调汁儿
Now we prepare the sauce.
# 加点儿淀粉
Add a bit starch.
# 生粉
Cornstarch.
# 勾芡
Thickening.
# 水淀粉
Water starch.
# 咱们锅得用凉油了 不能用热油了
Now we have to use cooled oil, instead of hot oil.
# 哎 热锅凉油
Check out, hot pot with cooled oil.
# 豆瓣酱得剁一下
We mince the thick broad-bean sauce.
# 泡椒也得剁一下
Pickled peppers need to be minced as well.
# 不剁一下颗粒太粗糙
Otherwise the particles would be too rough.
# 这二合酱啊
This is a bi-mixed sauce.
# 这个关键点是必须得炒透了
The key point is to stir fry those substances until well-done.
# 炒酥
All the way until crispy.
# 香油
Sesame oil.
# 加点姜末 先放姜末
Add some bruised ginger first.
# 葱花
Chopped scallions.
# 蒜蓉
Garlic sauce.
# 因为川菜小料必须得重
The seasoning sauce of Sichuan cuisine has to be very thick.
# 小料太重鱼香味才能出得来
The fish-flavored taste will emerge only if the seasoning is strong.
# 嘿 出来了香味
Hey, the tasty flavor comes out.
# 料酒（黄酒）
Rice wine.
# 这汁儿这么混呢
Why does the sauce look muddy?
# 传统手法 加芡儿了
Traditional method, thickening.
# 搅起来待会打熟了它就不混了
Keep stirring. The mixed sauce will go clean after well cooked.
# 顺一个方向转 不能胡搅和
Stir the sauce along one direction. Don’t stir randomly.
# 亮油
Put on some oil.
# 嘿 正好热油 热油最亮
Hey, exactly hot oil we need, looks brightest!
# 少来点葱花
Slightly add some chopped scallion.
# 咱把虾摆一下
Now we present the plate.
# 好
Ok
# 生活需要仪式感
An ordinary life needs a sense of ritual.
# 需要讲究点
Need a right amount of selectiveness.
# 讲究点
Yep, selectiveness.
# 皮酥肉嫩
Tender prawn with crispy shell.
# 鱼香脆皮虾
Fish-flavored crispy prawn.
# 嘿 小汁黏度合适 黏黏的
Hey, the thickness of the sauce is perfect. It’s sticky.
# 诶 小魏 这汁儿盛碗里什么意思
Hey Wei, how comes the sauce inside the bowl?
# 盛碗里就是蘸汁吃
You dip the prawn into the sauce.
# 这样它不会破坏它的形状
This way the prawn will keep the shape.
# 不会破坏它的脆度
And preserve its’ crispiness.
# 但是也不影响它的口味
And it won’t affect the taste.
# 好 吃起来
Wonderful, let’s eat!
# 我先蘸一下看看
I try it with the sauce first.
# 嗯 听着这声到脆嘿
Yummmm, you can tell how crispy it is by the sound!
# 都20分钟了
After 20 minutes,
# 还这么脆
It’s still very crispy.
# 我尝尝 来来 尝尝
I ll have some too.
# 皮也蘸点啊
Get some sauce on the shell as well.
汁兜多点
# 我也来一个
I ll have one too.
# 嘿 你听这声
Hey check out the sound.
# 声音
The sound.
# 倍儿脆啊
Extremely crispy.
# 其实我还是讲究味道
In fact, I valued the taste of food much.
# 这鱼香汁熬得真好 是吧
This fish-flavored sauce is so delicious! Right?
# 这个虾的形式也好
The shape of the prawns is delicate as well.
# 其实挺简单的
In fact, it’s not very hard.
# 对
Yep
# 不要觉得复杂
Don’t consider it too complicated.
# 那么还是在家亲手的操作操作
So, you’d better practice it at home. Give it a try.
# 片尾
I m Da ye, I m Er Bai, I m San shu. We are Lao Fan Gu.
Welcome to subscribe our Lao Fan Gu youtube channel.
Our Lao Fan Gu team is aiming to teach you how to cook. Teaching you guys some exquisite cooking skills. Hope you guys all like.
Hope food lovers all over the world like us, subscribe our channel, and turn on the notification.
At mean time, we send our greeting to Chinese friends all over the world. May everything go as you hope! May you be prosperous and wealthy.